Hello again! I'm Holly.
If you've been following this
program from start to finish,
you may remember me
from an earlier course
where I shared a bit about accessibility
and why it's so
important to keep it in
mind as a project manager.
So far, you've learned
the importance of managing,
communicating, and measuring quality.
This is a great opportunity to also
think about how to ensure the ways you
are collecting feedback
and the processes in place to measure
quality are fair and accessible.
First, if you are collecting
feedback through live interviews,
be sure to include an offer to provide
accommodations in your correspondence when
setting up the sessions.
You may get requests for
live captioning or an interpreter.
Other folks, such as those with anxiety or
on the autism spectrum,
may ask to see the questions in advance
so that they have time to think about and
prepare their answers.
Remember, what works for one person
may not work for another person,
even if those two people
have the same disability.
If you're conducting
an interview on location,
examine the space with
an accessibility lens,
like ensuring there's an accessible
path into the building and to the room
and that hallways are clear of
clutter that could block someone using
a wheelchair
or a walker or someone with
a visual impairment from easily and
safely moving through.
If sending a survey or
collecting feedback using technology,
check that the systems you
are using are fully accessible.
If you're unsure, contact the system
owner and ask if they are compliant
with the latest Web Content
Accessibility Guidelines, or WCAG.
Be prepared to provide questions and
collect responses in
an alternate manner, if needed.
Beyond collecting feedback,
as a project manager, it's important for
you to make accessibility part of
the conversation from the beginning,
especially if your project pertains
to a process or a product.
Oftentimes, incorporating accessible
features into a product is overlooked or
left to the final stages of a project.
and can lead to serious implications,
like launch delays, or worse,
a product that can't be used by
a percentage of the population.
Ensure your developers are familiar with
accessibility requirements at the start.
If they're not, help connect them with
appropriate resources or experts.
Include testers with various disabilities
in your usability testing whenever
possible,
and at the very least,
have the product tested for
adherence to accessibility guidelines.
In summary, think about
accessibility early and often, and
encourage others on your
project team to do so, too.
Coming up, you will practice
ways to measure quality and
learn more about managing changes, risk,
and so much more. Keep up the great work.